mlm.com 2005-12-10

# LexisNexis Privacy Statement

Privacy Statement  
---  
Your Privacy is Important to Us  
  
**Effective June 17, 2005  
**

**Our Commitment To Privacy**  
Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our home page and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.

This notice applies to all information collected from or submitted to the following LexisNexis Group ("LNG") Web sites, but to make this notice easier to read we will use the term "our Web site", which means lexisnexis.com, _lexis.com_ ®, nexis.comSM, lexisONE.com®, martindale.comSM and lawyers.comSM. Other LNG Web sites may operate under their own privacy notices.

Our Web site contains links to other Web sites operated by third parties. LNG is not responsible for the privacy practices or policies of such third party web sites and this Notice does not apply to those Web sites. 

Back to top >>

**Application of This Notice**  
This Notice applies only to the information collected by LNG from the users of our Web site. It does not apply to information collected by LNG in any other way, including offline. 

Back to top >>

**The Information We Collect**  
Our Web site is not set up to automatically collect personally identifiable information from each visitor to our Web site. It does recognize the home server of visitors, but not email addresses. For example, we can tell which Internet Service Provider our visitors use, but not the names, addresses or other information about our visitors that would allow us to identify the particular visitors to our Web site. This information is used only for internal purposes by our technical support staff.

Our Web site does track certain information about the visits to our Web site. For example, we compile statistics that show the numbers and frequency of visitors to our Web site and its individual pages. These aggregated statistics are used internally to improve our Web site and for product development and marketing purposes generally. Those aggregated statistics may also be provided to advertisers and other third parties, but again, the statistics contain no personal information and cannot be used to gather such information.

In a few areas on our Web site, we ask you to provide information that will enable us to verify whether you are entitled to access and use certain information, materials and services available from our Web site, or to enable us to enhance your site visit, to assist you with customer service or technical support issues, or to follow up with you after your visit, or to otherwise support your customer relationship with LNG. It is completely optional for you to participate. However, failure to participate may mean that you cannot access and use certain information, materials and services.

For example, we request information from you when you: 

  1. Log on to certain areas of our Web site, such as the _lexis.com_ ® Research System, where you may be prompted to provide us with your LexisNexis® ID number and password as a condition to gaining access to certain information, materials or services 
  2. Register or sign up to use a service such as _lexisONE.com_ ® 
  3. Subscribe to a newsletter or desire to be added to our mailing lists for other products or services 
  4. Place an order 
  5. Participate in a sweepstakes or other promotional offer 
  6. Provide feedback in an online survey. 

In each of the instances above, we typically ask for your name, email address, phone number, address, law practice information, product preference information, LexisNexis ID number and password, as well as other similar personal information that is needed to register or subscribe you to services or offers. On occasion, we may ask for additional information to enable us to provide you with access to and use of certain information, materials and services. In the case of newsletters or mailing lists, you will be able to "unsubscribe" to these mailings at any time. 

Back to top >>

**How We Use Information: LNG Only Uses Your Personal Information for Specific Purposes  
**The personal information you provide to us when using our Web site, such as your name, postal or email address or telephone number will be kept confidential and used to support your customer relationship with LNG, and to notify you of special offers, updated information and new products and services from LNG, offers from third parties that we think may be of interest to you, or used by LNG or third parties for the purpose of conducting market research or surveys on behalf of LNG. Agents or contractors of LNG who are given access to your personal information will be required to keep the information confidential and not use it for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for LNG.

LNG may enhance or merge your information collected at its Web site with data from third parties for purposes of marketing products or services to you.

With respect to network advertising companies (companies that manage and provide advertising for numerous unrelated companies), to the extent that LNG utilizes such advertising companies to provide advertisements on our Web site, LNG may provide them with your log-in name and any demographic information about you that we collect. Those advertising companies may combine that data with non-personally identifiable data collected by the advertising company from your computer solely for the purpose of delivering on our Web site advertisements that are targeted to you.

Circumstances may arise where we are required to disclose your personal information to third parties for purposes other than to support your customer relationship with LNG, such as in connection with a corporate divestiture or dissolution where we sell all or a portion of our business or assets (including our associated customer lists containing your personal information), or if disclosure is required by law or is pertinent to judicial or governmental investigations or proceedings. 

Back to top >>

**You Can Opt Out of Receiving Further Marketing from LNG at Any Time**  
We will send you information about our various products and services, or other products and services we feel may be of interest to you. Only LNG (or agents or contractors working on behalf of LNG and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you give us your personal information. Or, at any time you can easily opt out of receiving further marketing from LNG by emailing us at [ legalnotices@LexisNexis.com](mailto:legalnotices@LexisNexis.com). 

Back to top >>

**Our Commitment to Data Security**  
To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

Back to top >>

**How You Can Access or Correct Your Information  
**You can request a copy of the personally-identifiable information that LNG has collected about you via the Internet by contacting our Information Privacy Manager at the address below. You can also have factual inaccuracies in this information corrected by contacting this same person. 

Back to top >>

**How to Contact Us**  
If you would like to contact us for any reason regarding our privacy practices, please write us at the following address:

Privacy Information Manager, c/o LexisNexis, P.O. Box 933 Dayton, OH 45401, or call us at 1-800-831-2578.

Back to top >>
